Zhuo "Andrew" Zhang

Email: andrew.zhuo.zhang@outlook.com Cell: 978-239-3616 Skype: andrew.zhuo.zhang@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced in translation and interpretation between English and Chinese with a profound understanding and facility in both Anglophone and Chinese cultures; Background in ESL education and working with Peace Corps Volunteers as an intercultural liaison, maintaining a mindset which promotes cross-cultural communication; Techsavvy with good interpersonal skills and customer service experience from freelance translation work.

Academic Qualifications

Master of Translation and Interpretation (MTI) in English, Guizhou Normal University	Sep 2012 – Jul 2014
Bachelor of Arts in English, China University of Mining and Technology	Sep 2008 – Jul 2012

Working Experiences

Staff, Chatime at Allston, Boston

Dec 2016 - Present

Sales, beverage preparing and organizing at a highly fast-paced and multitasking environment

Volunteer, Boston Inquilinos Boricuas en Acción (IBA)

Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Providing residential and "Fair Foods" service in multi-cultural (English, Spanish, Chinese) environment

ESL Course Trainer for Teachers, Zunyi Normal College

Mar 2016 – May 2016

Instructing oral English class with real-life scenarios and engaging activities for non-major teachers

English Teacher, Zunyi Star Source Language School

Sep 2015 - Jan 2016

Fostered Reading, Listening and Speaking skills to middle school students

Teaching Assistant, Guizhou Medical University

Sep 2014 - Jul 2015

- Courses taught to English majors: Integrated College English for English Majors, Listening, Intensive Reading Course
- Office Secretary for Department of Translation in the College of Foreign Languages
- Counterpart/liaison to Peace Corps Volunteer Katherine Stevens and foreign teacher Richard Tossel

Translator, the 7th Asian Youth Animation, Comics and Digital Arts Contest

Nov 2013

Translator for Official Brochure and documents for the Contest and speeches and letters from guest lecturers

English Teacher, Guiyang EF Education First Language School

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

- Teaching English as a Second Language courses for 3-14 year old students
- Assisted in English immersion activities with students and foreign teachers, including cooking, book reading club

Language Skills

- Chinese: Native in reading, writing, listening and speaking
- English: Near Native in reading, writing, listening, and speaking
- Spanish: Intermediate proficiency in reading, listening, and speaking

IT Proficiency

- Familiarity with Windows, Mac and Linux Operating Systems and basic system administration.
- Familiarity with office suites and desktop publishing software, including iWork, Microsoft Office, Scribus, Corel Draw, Adobe Acrobat, and Computer Aided Translation (CAD) softwares and translation memory.